<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
  Copyright 2002-2004 The Apache Software Foundation or its licensors,
  as applicable.

  Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
  you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
  You may obtain a copy of the License at

      http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

  Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
  distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
  WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
  See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
  limitations under the License.
-->
<!DOCTYPE faqs PUBLIC "-//APACHE//DTD FAQ V2.0//EN" 
	"http://forrest.apache.org/dtd/faq-v20.dtd">
<faqs>
	<title>Log4js - Frequently Asked Questions</title>
	<authors>
		<person id="ssr" name="Stephan Strittmatter" />
	</authors>

	<faqsection id="general">
		<title>General</title>
		<faq id="usage">
			<question>How can I use Log4js?</question>
			<answer>
				<p>Have a look at the <a href="/examples.html">examples</a>. You 
					have only to add log4js.js as script to your HTML pages and 
					create a loggin object which you are using then in your 
					code for logging.</p>
				<p>For more details about the API, have a look at the 
					<a href="users-guide.html">users guide</a> and the <a 
					href="ext:log4js/apidocs">API documentation</a>.</p>
			</answer>
		</faq>
		<faq id="license">
			<question>Under which license is Log4js available?</question>
			<answer>
				<p>Log4js is licenced under the <a 
					href="ext:log4js/license">Apache License Version 
					2.0</a>.</p>
			</answer>
		</faq>
		<faq id="appender">
			<question>Why I have to set an Appender? What is an 
				Appender?</question>
			<answer>
				<p>Appenders are special implementations for different logging 
					behaviours. In some cases you probably want to log to a 
					popup window, in other situations you want to sent the 
					client logs to the server to store them there. </p>
				<p>log4js has a very flexible for these cirumstances and allows 
					own implementations for this. These are the appenders.</p>
				<p>There are some useful appenders available within log4js. 
					Have also a look at the <a href="ext:log4js/apidocs">API 
					documentation</a>:</p>
				<ul>
					<li><em>AjaxAppender:</em> Sends the logging content via 
						XmlHttpRequest to the server to log data on the 
						server.</li>
					<li><em>ConsoleAppender:</em> Creates a HTML console 
						(inline or separate window) to show the logs.</li>
					<li><em>JSAlertAppender:</em> For some circumstances 
						useful: Show alert boxes for each log.</li>
					<li><em>MetatagAppender:</em> Adds the loggs as meta 
						tags.</li>
					<li><em>FileAppender:</em> Creates a local file to write 
						the logs in. Works with Mozilla and Internet 
						Explorer.</li>
					<li><em>WindowsEventAppender:</em> Sends the logs to the 
						Windows System Events. Works only with Internet 
						Explorer.</li>
					<li><em>MozJSConsoleAppender:</em> Sends the logs to the 
						Mozilla JavaScript console</li>
					<li><em>SafariJSConsoleAppender:</em> Sends the logs to the 
						Safari JavaScript console</li>
					<li><em>OperaJSConsoleAppender:</em> Sends the logs to the 
						Opera JavaScript console</li>
				</ul>
				<p>Probably you have also an appender, to share with the 
					comunitiy?</p>
			</answer>
		</faq>
		<faq id="layout">
			<question>How do I use Layouts?</question>
			<answer>
				<p>The Layouts give you the possibility to format the logs in a 
					specific way. For example, it is possible to format as HTML 
					or XML. Some appenders require a specific layout to work 
					correctly. </p>
				<p>Following layouts are available:</p>
				<ul>
					<li><em>JSONLayout:</em> formats the log entrys as JSON 
						object, which can be read by different programming 
						languages. Often it is more useful than XML because of 
						the smaller footprints.</li>
					<li><em>XMLLayout:</em> formats the log entries as XML 
						structure. The structure is very simmilar to the XML 
						structure of Apachees log4j</li>
					<li><em>HTMLLayout:</em> formats the log entry as HTML 
						div-element</li>
				</ul>
			</answer>
		</faq>
		<faq id="remotelogging">
			<question>Can I log the data from the client on the 
				server?</question>
			<answer>
				<p> Logging is useful during development. Then the log output 
					is useful within ConsoleAppender for example. But logging 
					is much more usefule within production systems, where your 
					application is out in the wild area. There you can not 
					debug and the users just report errors. Having no logs it 
					is difficult to understand what happend in complex 
					environments. </p>
				<p> For this circumstances we designed the AJAXAppender! The 
					AJAXAppender sned all the logs collected on the client to a 
					specific url on the server. There you can process them 
					using log4j, log4php or by your own. To improve the 
					performance a threshold could be defined. The log entries 
					are send then in blocks. </p>
			</answer>
		</faq>
	</faqsection>
	<faqsection id="docs">
		<title>Documentation</title>
		<faq id="forrest">
			<question>How can I help write documentation?</question>
			<answer>
				<p> This project uses <a href="ext:forrest">Apache Forrest</a> 
					to generate documentation from XML. Please download a copy 
					of Forrest, which can be used to <a 
					href="ext:forrest/validation">validate</a>, <a 
					href="ext:forrest/webapp">develop</a> and render a project 
					site. </p>
				<p>It is also possible to write some documentation at our 
					<a href="ext:log4js/wiki">wiki</a> which is much more
					userfriendly if you want to write only short things. If there
					are good articles we will probably move them to the log4js site.</p>
			</answer>
		</faq>
		<!-- More faqs or parts here -->
	</faqsection>
	<!-- More faqs or parts here -->
</faqs>